BRIAN CHARLES O'REILLY

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

416.998.2473 | BRIANCHARLESOREILLY@GMAIL.COM briancharlesoreilly.com | github.com/briancharlesoreilly

PERSONAL BACKGROUND

A creative at heart with solid leadership and managerial experience in the hospitality industry as a (former) small business owner. Classical training in solid wood cabinet making led to several years of bespoke furniture design and building, rounding out a lively and unique work history. Quick to learn, highly adaptable, with a penchant for forward thinking and novel technologies, such as immersion in developing web 3 technologies. Outside of work you'll find me obsessing over gaming (love RPGs), music (I've toured North America six times), and books (bury me in the library) as well as honing my backend skills (currently Python) and Ethereum/blockchain coding (Solidity).

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3 and SCSS
- Responsive Web Design
- Web Accessibility Standards
- Javascript (es6) & jQuery
- React
- RESTful APIs & Firebase
- Python (learning)
- Solidity (learning)
- AWS Certification (learning)

SPECIALIZATIONS

- Team Building
- Planning & Logistics
- Advanced Financial Literacy
- Budget Forecasting
- Revenue Growth
- Innovative Technological Adaptation
- Small Business Acumen

PROJECTS

- Roleplaying board game companion API.
- Entertainment/Social Media Quote API app.
- Upcoming React Juno Project 1.

WHERE:

Cell: (416) 998 2473

Email: briancharlesoreilly@gmail.com Location: West End, Toronto ON

WORK HISTORY

Bar Manager / Owner NORTHERN BELLE, 2015 - 2021

- Created short, mid, and long term roadmap in competitive industry.
- Provided successful cost-reduction solutions during pandemic (temporary 40% reduction in fixed monthly overhead & rent relief).
- Grew business from debt governed inception (- \$80k debt in 2017) to cash positive state suitable for expansion or sale (+ 200k evaluation in 2021)
- Researched and updated technological assets to streamline operations while respecting traditional sector needs.

Cabinet Maker & Furniture Design SON OF A WOODCUTTER, 2016 - 2018

- Designed, milled, and manufactured bespoke solid wood furniture for high end clients.
- Digital marketing of company catalog through social media.
- Pivoted between front facing customer service role and back end design, creation and distribution of product.

Bar & Cafe Manager

NORTHWOOD, 2013 - 2015

- Inventory / Product supply chain director.
- Oversaw employee hiring, training & product knowledge.
- Scheduled staff of 15 20.
- Directly controlled budgetary spending, and setting / expanding revenue goals for business doing \$315, 000 sales a year (pre pandemic).

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Juno College of Technology (Toronto ON)WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSIVE BOOTCAMP, 2022

- Web development HTML & CSS accelerated program
- JavaScript accelerated program

Humber College (Toronto ON)

CABINET MAKING, 2016- Deans list with Honours

St. Francis Xavier University (Antigonish NS)

BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION. 2004
- Partial Degree - Deans list with Honours

J.L. Ilsley High School (Halifax NS) HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA, 2003

- Vice President of Student Council
- Winner of Regional High School Robotics competition.
- Party Leader of Model Parliament.
- Mathlete